A Finding Aid to the William Chapin Seitz Papers, circa 1930-1995, in the Archives of American Art AAA.seitwill
Archives of American Art
William Chapin Seitz papers
circa 1930-1995
AAA.seitwill
Archives of American Art
32.5 Linear feet
The papers of educator, painter, and art historian William Chapin Seitz measure 32.5 linear feet and date from circa 1930-1995. The collection includes biographical information, correspondence, notebooks, subject and people files, thesis research files, interviews and lecture recordings, teaching files, personal business records, scattered printed materials, photographs, and artwork. The bulk of the papers focus on Seitz's research and teaching career.
Seitz, William Chapin
Immediate Source of Acquisition note
The William Chapin Seitz papers were donated to the Archives of American Art by Seitz's widow, Irma Seitz, in 1975 and 2003. A transcript of an interview with Mark Tobey by Seitz was donated by Rebecca Massie Lane in 1988. Seitz gave these transcripts to Lane for her graduate work and they remined in her possession after his death.
Related Archival Materials note
The Museum of Modern Art Archives in New York City holds the William C. Seitz papers which contain exhibition files and records relating to an interview with Marcel Duchamp. Correspondence relating to the debate concerning the viability of Seitz's dissertation are found in the Alfred H. Barr, Jr. papers also at the Museum of Modern Art Archives.
Conditions Governing Access note
Use of original papers requires an appointment. Use of archival audiovisual recordings with no duplicate access copy requires advance notice.
Biographical/Historical note
William Chapin Seitz (1914-1974) was an art historian and scholar, painter, educator, and museum curator who worked primarily in New York and Virginia. He completed the first dissertation on Abstract Expressionism while a student at Princeton University in 1955.
Born in 1914 in Buffalo, New York, William Chapin Seitz studied at the Albright Art School at the University of Buffalo and the Art Institute of Buffalo. Seitz met artist Irma J. Siegelman, whom he married in 1938. Due to the Depression, he left school and worked with the Federal Arts Project in New York City in the 1930s and worked as an aircraft fuel cell deigner for the Hewitt Rubber Company during World War II. Returning to the University of Buffalo after the war, Seitz completed his undergraduate degree and remained by accepting a teaching job.
Although he saw success as a painter and exhibited in one-man shows, Seitz focused his career in academia and enrolled at Princeton University for a graduate degree in Art History. Princeton faculty held divided views on Seitz's desire to write a dissertation on the Abstract Expressionist movement and debated the subject for over a year. Seitz's dissertation topic was eventually approved and in addition to writing the first dissertation on Abstract Expressionism, Seitz received the first PhD in Modern Art from Princeton. Seitz remained at Princeton as an assistant professor and advised students such as Frank Stella.
In 1960, he accepted a job as a curator at the Museum of Modern Art in New York City. At MOMA, Seitz curated The Art of Assemblage (1961), The Responsive Eye (1965), and an exhibition on Monet (1960). Other MOMA exhibitions focused on artists Mark Tobey, Arshile Gorky, and Hans Hofmann. Additionally, he served as director of the Rose Art Museum of Brandeis University from 1965-1970. During that time, Seitz organized the United States exhibition at the Ninth Biennial in Sao Paulo (1967) and the Seventh Biennial of Canadian Painting (1968). In 1971, Seitz returned to teaching at the University of Virginia in Charlottesville, Virginia and was the Visiting Kress Professor at the National Gallery of Art from 1972-1973.
In addition to his successes in painting, education, and the curatorial field, Seitz was an accomplished writer. He published many articles, essays, and books on art and artists including Art in the Age of Aquarius, on which he worked until his death.
William Seitz died of cancer in 1974.
Scope and Contents note
The papers of educator, painter, and art historian William Chapin Seitz measure 32.5 linear feet and date from circa 1930-1995. The collection includes biographical information, correspondence, notebooks, subject and people files, thesis research files, interviews and lecture recordings, teaching files, personal business records, scattered printed materials, photographs, and artwork. The bulk of the papers focus on Seitz's research and teaching career.
Biographical materials consist of resumes and CV's, identification cards including one from the WPA, documents from the memorial held at the University of Virginia for Seitz, poetry written by Irma for William on their wedding anniversaries, and x-rays.
The majority of Seitz's correspondence is professional and concerns job offers and opportunities, lectures requests, recommendation letters for Seitz and for others by Seitz, the Kress Fellowship, exhibitions, awards, and organizations. Also found are posthumus materials to Irma Seitz concerning book royalites. Personal correspondence is scattered and includes condolence letters sent to Irma.
Personal business records focus on Seitz's personal art collection, copyright information, publishing records including royalty statements, reports, scholarship and fellowship information, and professional organization membership records.
The bulk of the collection consists of research and writing files which include notebooks, subject and people files, thesis research files and drafts, general research which include writings by Seitz, card files, and recordings of lectures and interviews. Subject and people files may include correspondence, printed materials, research notes, photographs, works of art, and writings concerning and by artists, art historians, curators, subjects, and art movements. Research files are found for Dore Ashton, Alfred H. Barr Jr., William Baziotes, Bruce Conner, Rene D'Harnoncourt, Marcel Duchamp, Arshile Gorky, Adolph Gottlieb, Rockne Krebs, George Segal, James Rosati, and Frank Stella among many others. Also found are research materials on Claude Monet, some of which are written in French.
Teaching files contains extensive reference material likely used by Seitz during his career as well as correspondence, exams, and lecture materials used in specific classes.
Printed material is scattered and includes clippings, exhibition announcements, and articles. Exhibition announcements and catalogs are for Seitz's personal works and for exhibitions he curated.
The bulk of the photographs are of works of art by William Seitz, Irma Seitz, and others which were likely owned by Seitz. Also found are phtographs of exhibition installations at the Univeristy of Virginia and scattered photographs of Seitz with others.
Artwork include several pencil sketches by Seitz, two works by Ellen Banks-Woodson, and a sketch by Phil Elliott.
Arrangement note
The collection is arranged as 8 series:
Series 1: Biographical Information, 1930s-1974 (Box 1; 7 folders)
Series 2: Correspondence, 1945-1995 (Boxes 1-2; 1.6 linear feet)
Series 3: Personal Business Records, circa 1947-1990 (Boxes 2-3; 0.4 linear feet)
Series 4: Research and Writing Files, 1940s-1970s (Boxes 4-26; 23.5 linear feet)
Series 5: Teaching Files, 1945-1970s (Boxes 27-31, OV 34-35; 5 linear feet)
Series 6: Printed Material, 1937-1984 (Boxes 31-2; 0.5 linear feet)
Series 7: Photographs, 1940s-1981 (Box 32, 33; 11 folders)
Series 8: Artwork, circa 1950s-1972 (Box 32, 33; 6 folders)
Ashton, Dore; Banks-Woodson, Ellen; Barr, Alfred Hamilton, 1902-; Baziotes, William, 1912-1963; Conner, Bruce; D'Harnoncourt, Rene, 1901-1968; Duchamp, Marcel, 1887-1968; Elliott, Philip Clarkson, 1903-1985; Gorky, Arshile, 1904-1948; Gottlieb, Adolph, 1903-1974; Krebs, Rockne, 1938-; Monet, Claude, 1840-1926; Rosati, James, 1912-; Segal, George, 1924-2000; Seitz, Irma; Stella, Frank; University of Virginia. -- Faculty; Art historians--Virginia--Charlottesville; Awards; Drafts (documents); Educators--Virginia; Interviews; Lectures; Notebooks; Painters--Virginia--Charlottesville; Photographs; Poems; Resumes; Sketches; Sound recordings
- Biographical Information, 1930s-1974; Series 1; 7 Folders Box 1
  Scope and Contents note
  This series contains William Seitz's resumes and CV's; identification cards including a Works Progress Administration for New York City card; materials concerning a memorial held after Seitz's death at the University of Virginia including correspondence, artwork, writings, speeches, clipings, and condolence cards; poetry written by Irma Seitz for William on the anniversary of their marriage; and x-rays.
  - CV's and Resumes, 1974; 1950s; 2 Folders (Box 1, Folder 1-2)
  - Identification Cards, 1930s (Box 1, Folder 3)
  - UVA Memorial, 1974; 2 Folders (Box 1, Folder 4-5)
  - Poetry by Irma Seitz, for William Seitz, 1960s (Box 1, Folder 6)
  - X-Rays, feet, 1943 (Box 1, Folder 7)
- Correspondence, 1945-1995; Series 2; 1.6 Linear feet Boxes 1-2
  This series consists of incoming and copies of outgoing correspondence, the bulk of which is professionally focused. Correspondence relates to job opportunities, recommendations for Seitz and for others by Seitz, correspondence from organizations to which Seitz belonged, and materials sent and received while serving as the Kress Fellow at the National Gallery of Art, at the Rose Art Musuem, and as associate curator at the Museum of Modern Art. Researchers should note that more correspondence can be found within the Research and Writing Files series. Also found are condolence letters sent to Irma Seitz.
  Arrangement note
  Correspondence is arranged into rough chronological order. Materials organized by Seitz are labeled by subject at the beginning of this series with general correspondence at the end.
  - Kress Fellowship, 1971-2; 5 Folders (Box 1, Folder 8-12)
  - Stanford, Job Opportunity, 1965 (Box 1, Folder 13)
  - University of Virginia, Salary and Hiring, 1970-1972 (Box 1, Folder 14)
  - Offers for Faculty Positions, 1950s (Box 1, Folder 15)
  - Recommendation Letters, 1965-1969; 2 Folders (Box 1, Folder 16-17)
  - Recommendation Letters, for Others (Box 1, Folder 18)
  - Lecture Requests, 1968 (Box 1, Folder 19)
  - Lecture Requests, Declined, 1966-1965; 2 Folders (Box 1, Folder 20-1)
  - Lecture Requests, Repeated, 1966-1967 (Box 1, Folder 22)
  - Regarding Spoerri Sculpture, 1970s (Box 1, Folder 23)
  - Regarding Monet Research and Article, 1956-1959 (Box 1, Folder 24)
  - State University College Exhibition, 1968 (Box 1, Folder 25)
  - "Quality in Sculpture", 1969 (Box 1, Folder 26)
  - Concerning Artists and Exhibitions, 1970s (Box 1, Folder 27)
  - Rose Art Museum, 1968-1971 (Box 1, Folder 28)
  - Pepsico International Sculpture Exhibition, 1972 (Box 1, Folder 29)
  - Associate Curator of MoMA, 1960s (Box 1, Folder 30)
  - Syed Muhammed Award, 1966-1968 (Box 1, Folder 31)
  - College Art Association, 1956-1960s; 2 Folders (Box 2, Folder 1-2)
  - Art International, 1966-1967 (Box 2, Folder 3)
  - Art in the Age of Aquarius, 1970-1979 (Box 2, Folder 4)
  - Black Mountain College, 1970s (Box 2, Folder 5)
  - George Herms Exhibition for Seitz, 1981 (Box 2, Folder 6)
  - National Gallery of Art, undated; 1985 (Box 2, Folder 7)
  - Book Royalties, 1971-1975 (Box 2, Folder 8)
  - Condolence Letters, 1974 (Box 2, Folder 9)
  - Irma Seitz Correspondence, 1975-1979 (Box 2, Folder 10)
  - General Correspondence, 1945-1973; 18 Folders (Box 2, Folder 11-28)
- Personal Business Records, circa 1947-1990; Series 3; 0.4 Linear feet Boxes 2-3
  This series consists of materials relating to William Seitz's personal art collection, including donations, gifts, loans, inventories, and appraisals; copyright information; royalty statements and other materials relating to Seitz's published works; fellowship, grant, and scholarship materials; a project report for the art museum of the University of Washington; and travel papers.
  - Donations to UVA, 1975 (Box 2, Folder 29)
  - Donations to Firestone Museum, Princeton University, 1985 (Box 2, Folder 30)
  - Donations to Newark Museum, 1985 (Box 2, Folder 31)
  - Donations to National Gallery of Art, 1982 (Box 2, Folder 32)
  - Loan Agreements, 1961-1970 (Box 2, Folder 33)
  - Copyright Information, 1973-1979 (Box 2, Folder 34)
  - Deeds of Gift, Acknowledgements, undated; 1975 (Box 2, Folder 35)
  - Estate of George Seitz, 1952 (Box 2, Folder 36)
  - Sales Records, 1965 (Box 2, Folder 37)
  - Shipping Receipts, 1966 (Box 2, Folder 38)
  - Art Inventory, Personal, 1975 (Box 3, Folder 1)
  - Forms, MoMA, 1960s (Box 3, Folder 2)
  - Lists of Works of Art, 1970 (Box 3, Folder 3)
  - Appraisal Information, undated; 1980; 2 Folders (Box 3, Folder 4-5)
  - William Chapin Seitz Memorial Collection, 1972 (Box 3, Folder 6)
    Includes photos of installations of works of art
  - Exhibitions, Juried, 1967 (Box 3, Folder 7)
  - Paintings by Seitz, Sale and Exhibition, 1949-1951 (Box 3, Folder 8)
  - Royalty Statements, 1960-1971 (Box 3, Folder 9)
  - Book Prefaces and Commentaries, 1970s (Box 3, Folder 10)
  - Acknowledgements for Art as Experience, circa 1960s (Box 3, Folder 11)
  - Publishing Records, undated; 1975; 2 Folders (Box 3, Folder 12-13)
  - Project Report, University of Washington, 1969; undated (Box 3, Folder 14)
  - Fellowship and Scholarship Information, 1950s (Box 3, Folder 15)
  - Fulbright Scholarship, undated; 1958; 2 Folders (Box 3, Folder 16-17)
  - Copies of Recommendations for Seitz, by Others, 1960s (Box 3, Folder 18)
  - College Art Association, Board Materials, 1960-1974; 3 Folders (Box 3, Folder 19-21)
  - Rose Art Museum, Working Information, 1960s (Box 3, Folder 22)
  - Travel Papers, 1956; undated (Box 3, Folder 23)
  - Miscellaneous Receipts, circa 1947; undated (Box 3, Folder 24)
- Research and Writing Files, 1940s-1970s; Series 4; 23.5 Linear feet Boxes 4-26
  William Chapin Seitz's research and writing files comprise the bulk of the collection and span the 1940s-1970s. Files are found for artists, art movements, museums, art historians, and others. Contents of the files vary but typically include correspondence, notes, writings, printed materials, photographs, and sound recordings of lectures and interviews. Research files are found for Dore Ashton, Alfred H. Barr Jr., William Baziotes, Bruce Conner, Rene D'Haroncourt, Marcel Duchamp, Arshile Gorky, Adolph Gottlieb, Rockne Krebs, George Segal, James Rosati, and Frank Stella among many others. Also found are research materials on Claude Monet, some of which are written in French.
  The series is arranged as 6 subseries:
  4.1: Notebooks, 1957-1968
  4.2: Subject and People Files, 1940s-1970s
  4.3: Thesis Writings and Research, 1950s
  4.4: General Research, 1950s-1970s
  4.5: Card Files, 1940s-1960s
  4.6: Interview and Lecture Recordings, 1960s-1970s
  - Notebooks, 1957-1968; 4.1
    This subseries consists of notebooks used by Seitz during trips, concerning exhibitions, research, etc. The titles of each notebook were written on the front by Seitz. Notebook V and XI are missing.
    - I, Canada Book, 1968 March-April (Box 3, Folder 25)
    - II, 1968 March - April (Box 3, Folder 26)
    - III, 1968 March - April (Box 3, Folder 27)
    - IV, Trip to France, 1950s (Box 3, Folder 28)
    - VI, 1957 April 9-10 (Box 3, Folder 29)
    - VII, 1957 June (Box 3, Folder 30)
    - VIII, Monet, 1958-1959 (Box 3, Folder 31)
    - IX, circa 1959 (Box 3, Folder 32)
    - X, Paris, 1957 (Box 3, Folder 33)
    - XII, 1958 (Box 3, Folder 34)
    - XIII, 1958-1959 (Box 3, Folder 35)
    - XV, circa 1957 (Box 3, Folder 36)
    - XIV, Exhibition Plan, 1959 July (Box 3, Folder 37)
    - R/E I, circa 1964 (Box 4, Folder 1)
    - R/E II, circa 1964 (Box 4, Folder 2)
    - R/E III, circa 1964 (Box 4, Folder 3)
    - R/E VI, circa 1964 (Box 4, Folder 4)
    - R/E V, circa 1964 (Box 4, Folder 5)
    - R/E VI, circa 1964 (Box 4, Folder 6)
    - Color Vocabulary, circa 1950s (Box 4, Folder 7)
    - General Notes, Art and Books, circa 1960s (Box 4, Folder 8)
    - Mangritte, 1965 (Box 4, Folder 9)
    - Michelangelo, circa 1950s (Box 4, Folder 10)
    - Monet--Boston, Cambridge, Washington, 1956 Summer - 1957 February (Box 4, Folder 11)
    - Wildenstein Monets, circa late 1950s (Box 4, Folder 12)
    - "S. F.,", 1960 January 4-24 (Box 4, Folder 13)
    - 5, 1961 January (Box 4, Folder 14)
    - Composition Book, 1965 April 26 (Box 4, Folder 15)
  - People and Subject Files, 1940s-1970s; 4.2
    This subseries comprises the bulk of the William Chapin Seitz papers. People and subject files are organized in rough alphabetical order and include a wide variety of types of materials, such as correspondence, printed materials, research files, notes, photographs, works of art, and writings concerning and by the artists, art historians, museum professionals, subjects, and movements.
    - Abstract Expressionism, circa 1960s; 7 Folders (Box 4, Folder 16-22)
    - Abstract Art, Origins, 1960s (Box 4, Folder 23)
    - Adrian, Mark, 1970 (Box 4, Folder 24)
    - Agam, Yaacor, 1960s (Box 4, Folder 25)
    - Ashton, Dore, 1960s (Box 4, Folder 26)
    - Alberti, Architectural Theory, 1949 (Box 4, Folder 27)
    - American Association of Museums, 1960s (Box 4, Folder 28)
    - American Consciousness, 1970s (Box 4, Folder 29)
    - American Council of Learned Societies, 1950s-1960s (Box 4, Folder 30)
    - American Federation of Arts, 1950s (Box 4, Folder 31)
    - American Impressionism, 1970s (Box 4, Folder 32)
    - American Art at Mid-Century, 1973 (Box 5, Folder 1)
    - American Art, 1960-1970 (Box 5, Folder 2)
    - Ancient Art, 1960s (Box 5, Folder 3)
    - Anti-Modern Art, 1950s-1970s (Box 5, Folder 4)
    - Antiques, 1970 (Box 5, Folder 5)
    - Applied Art, 1960s (Box 5, Folder 6)
    - Aquarius, Astrology, 1970-1970 (Box 5, Folder 7)
    - Architects, 1970s (Box 5, Folder 8)
    - Architecture, 1970s (Box 5, Folder 9)
    - Arista Gallery, 1938 (Box 5, Folder 10)
    - Art and [illegible], 1970s (Box 5, Folder 11)
    - Art and Government, 1960s-1970s (Box 5, Folder 12)
    - Art and Literature, 1966-1970 (Box 5, Folder 13)
    - Art and Politics, 1970-1972; 2 Folders (Box 5, Folder 14-15)
    - Art and Taxes, 1960s-1970s (Box 5, Folder 16)
    - Art and Theater, 1960s-1970s (Box 5, Folder 17)
    - Art Dealer Association, 1973 (Box 5, Folder 18)
    - Art Definition, 1964 (Box 5, Folder 19)
    - Art Education, 1970s (Box 5, Folder 20)
    - Art Films, 1960s (Box 5, Folder 21)
    - Art Historians, 1970s (Box 5, Folder 22)
    - Art Law, 1960s-1970s (Box 5, Folder 23)
    - Art Market, 1960s-1970s; 2 Folders (Box 5, Folder 24-25)
    - Art Market Magazine, 1960s-1970s (Box 5, Folder 26)
    - Art Scene, 1960s-1970s (Box 5, Folder 27)
    - Art, Ridiculous or Bad, 1960s-1970s (Box 5, Folder 28)
    - Art, Black, 1970s (Box 5, Folder 29)
    - Art, Communist, 1960s (Box 5, Folder 30)
    - Art Establishment, 1960s (Box 5, Folder 31)
    - Art, Russian, 1960s (Box 5, Folder 32)
    - Art Technology, 1960s (Box 5, Folder 33)
    - Artists Biographies, 1960s-1970s (Box 5, Folder 34)
    - Artists, Boston and New England, 1960s; 2 Folders (Box 5, Folder 35-36)
    - Artists Clubs, 1950s (Box 5, Folder 37)
    - Artists Crisis, 1970-1971 (Box 5, Folder 38)
    - Artists Groups, 1950s-1970s (Box 5, Folder 39)
    - Artists Lists, 1960s-1970s; 2 Folders (Box 5, Folder 40-41)
    - Artists Lists, 1960s-1970s; 2 Folders (Box 6, Folder 1-2)
    - Artists Assemblage, 1950s-1960s; 2 Folders (Box 6, Folder 3-4)
    - Artists Assemblage Panel, 1961 (Box 6, Folder 5)
    - Artists Statements, 1970s (Box 6, Folder 6)
    - Artists Studios, 1960s-1970s (Box 6, Folder 7)
    - Artists Tapes, 1960s-1970s (Box 6, Folder 8)
    - Artists, Virginia, 1960s (Box 6, Folder 9)
    - Albers, Josef, 1960s (Box 6, Folder 10)
    - Asia, 1970s (Box 6, Folder 11)
    - Association of Art Museum Directors, 1960s (Box 6, Folder 12)
    - Atlantic Brief Lives, 1960s-1970s (Box 6, Folder 13)
    - Avant Garde, 1960s-1970s; 2 Folders (Box 6, Folder 14-15)
    - Bahai, 1963 (Box 6, Folder 16)
    - Baltimore, Maryland, circa 1964 (Box 6, Folder 17)
    - Barr, Alfred, 1952-1973 (Box 6, Folder 18)
    - Bauhaus, 1969-1970 (Box 6, Folder 19)
    - Baziotes, William, 1950s-1960s (Box 6, Folder 20)
    - Beuys, Joseph, 1960s-1970s (Box 6, Folder 21)
    - Biennial, Venice, 1960s-1970s (Box 6, Folder 22)
    - Biennial, Sao Paolo, 1960s (Box 6, Folder 23)
    - Biography, Rickey, 1970s; 2 Folders (Box 6, Folder 24-25)
    - Biographies, Not Artists, 1970s (Box 6, Folder 26)
    - Black Culture, Not Art, 1960s-1970s (Box 6, Folder 27)
    - Black Mountain College, circa 1950s (Box 6, Folder 28)
    - Blurbs, 1960s-1970s (Box 6, Folder 29)
    - Bocour, Leonard, 1970s (Box 6, Folder 30)
    - Books, Current and Relevant, 1970s (Box 6, Folder 31)
    - Books, Art Historical, 1970s (Box 6, Folder 32)
    - Books, 1960s-1970s (Box 7, Folder 1)
    - Boston, Massachusetts, 1960s (Box 7, Folder 2)
    - Boston Scene, 1960s-1970s (Box 7, Folder 3)
    - Brown, J. Carter, 1974 (Box 7, Folder 4)
    - Brush Techniques, 1949; 1970s (Box 7, Folder 5)
    - Cage, John, 1960s-1970s (Box 7, Folder 6)
    - Calderara, Antonio, 1970s (Box 7, Folder 7)
    - California School, 1948-1972 (Box 7, Folder 8)
    - California, 1960s-1970s (Box 7, Folder 9)
    - Calligraphy, 1972 (Box 7, Folder 10)
    - Camping, 1970s (Box 7, Folder 11)
    - Canada, 1970s (Box 7, Folder 12)
      (Artists Lists and Data)
    - Canadian Art, 1967-1970 (Box 7, Folder 13)
    - Canady, John, 1960s (Box 7, Folder 14)
    - Categories of Art, 1970s (Box 7, Folder 15)
    - Cezanne, Paul, 1960s (Box 7, Folder 16)
    - Change, 1960s-1970s (Box 7, Folder 17)
    - Charlottesville, Virginia, 1970s (Box 7, Folder 18)
    - Chicago, Illinois, 1970s (Box 7, Folder 19)
    - Christo, 1972 (Box 7, Folder 20)
    - Collage, 1960s-1970s (Box 7, Folder 21)
    - Collage, American, 1960s (Box 7, Folder 22)
    - Collage, Objects, 1960s (Box 7, Folder 23)
    - Collectors and Collecting, 1960s-1970s; 5 Folders (Box 7, Folder 24-28)
    - Club, 1960s (Box 7, Folder 29)
    - College Art Association, 1970s; 2 Folders (Box 7, Folder 30-31)
    - Color, 1970s (Box 7, Folder 32)
    - Comparative Art, 1970s (Box 7, Folder 33)
    - Communes, 1970s (Box 7, Folder 34)
    - Conceptual Art, 1970s; 2 Folders (Box 8, Folder 1-2)
    - Conner, Bruce, 1960-1961; 3 Folders (Box 8, Folder 3-5)
      (Includes assemblage mail art)
    - Conservation, 1970s (Box 8, Folder 6)
    - Constructivism, 1970s (Box 8, Folder 7)
    - Cooper-Union, 1963-1965 (Box 8, Folder 8)
    - Corbett, Edward, 1950s (Box 8, Folder 9)
    - Cornell, Joseph, 1950s-1960s (Box 8, Folder 10)
    - Counter Culture, 1966-1972; 3 Folders (Box 8, Folder 11-13)
    - Creative Process, 1960s (Box 8, Folder 14)
    - Criticism, 1960s-1970s (Box 8, Folder 15)
    - Critics, 1967 (Box 8, Folder 16)
    - Cubism, 1971 (Box 8, Folder 17)
    - Current, 1960s-1970s (Box 8, Folder 18)
    - d'Arcangelo, Allan, 1970s (Box 8, Folder 19)
    - d'Harnoncourt, Rene, undated; 1959 (Box 8, Folder 20)
    - Dada, 1960s-1970s (Box 8, Folder 21)
    - Dance, 1971 (Box 8, Folder 22)
    - Davis, Gene, 1973 (Box 8, Folder 23)
    - de Kooning, Willem, 1950s-1972; 3 Folders (Box 8, Folder 24-26)
    - Dealers, 1960s-1970s (Box 8, Folder 27)
    - Death, 1971 (Box 8, Folder 28)
    - Decades, 1970s (Box 8, Folder 29)
      (20s and 30s)
    - Decorative Arts, 1970s (Box 8, Folder 30)
    - Delacroix, Eugene, 1950s (Box 8, Folder 31)
    - Der Strum, 1971 (Box 8, Folder 32)
    - Destruction in Art, Auto-Destruction, 1960s-1970s (Box 8, Folder 33)
    - di Suvero, Mark, 1960s (Box 8, Folder 34)
    - Drawing, early 1970s (Box 8, Folder 35)